( somber orchestral music )
( gasps )
( soft pensive orchestral music )
( clattering , banging )
I 'm sorry .
( mouthing ) I 'm sorry ?
( hissing )
( sobbing )
( pensive orchestral music )
- ( glass shattering ) - MAN : Sir , she 's breaking out !
( man gagging , coughing )
- ( grunts ) - ( thuds )
( energetic chase music )
- SOLDIER 1 : Go , go ! - SOLDIER 2 : What are we looking for ?
SOLDIER 1 : She jumped over the fence .
( helicopter whirring )
SOLDIER 1 : She jumped over the fence !
( flares firing )
- ( helicopter whirring ) - ( suspenseful music )
( train horn blaring )
- ( grunting ) - ( thud )
( helicopters whirring )
A couple of trains came through here
around about the time she escaped .
Do you think she could have gotten this far in that time ?
Is she that fast ?
She is that fast .
( playful orchestral music )
MAN : And this , too .
- CLERK : $ 3.10 . - MAN : Three dollars and 10 cents ?
CLERK : Right .
Here 's your change .
MAN : Thank you .
CLERK : Can I help you ?
The total is $ 17.95 .
Here 's your card .
Are you gonna buy those ?
PORTER : Have a nice trip .
MAN : It 's a brown tweed bag
with leather trim , kind of like a duffel .
Do you see it anywhere ?
PORTER : No , Sir .
The porter said he was gonna bring it up and put it on the cart .
This is the cart , there 's no bag here .
( train crossing chiming )
( clicking )
ANNOUNCER : Government authorities said
this was the largest earthquake to strike
in the urban area in nearly - -
ANNOUNCER 2 : He 's riding Greased Lightning .
( laughing )
That was Shorty Kincaid .
Enjoy the view .
( clattering , wood breaking )
Excuse me .
MAN ON T.V. : We shouldn 't be seen together .
Father hasn 't been dead more than 48 hours .
Do you think Arliss suspects ?
WOMAN ON T.V. : No , it 's not too soon for us to be together .
( knocking )
Tickets , please .
Oh , are you traveling by yourself ?
What , you 're 12 ?
Someone gonna meet you in Los Angeles ?
We 'll say that you 're 11 .
That way you only have to pay half-price .
( door bangs shut )
( clanking )
MAN : I can 't believe our little girl did this .
She 's not a little girl .
DNA typing and material found in those wounds
proves it was her .
She could be anywhere ,
Chicago , Las Vegas , Los Angeles , anywhere .
We should stop all the trains .
And have the railroad and local police
ask a million questions we can 't answer ?
We 'll put key personnel at every stop along these lines .
I want a team to track her .
Hunt her down .
Good morning , Jill .
Thank you for taking care of my cat .
We 'll take very good care of your cat .
I won 't be gone for very long .
Take care of yourself .
Bye-bye .
WOMAN : Are you still having problems with the people at work ?
They point their finger at me saying
I 'm the weird one , I 'm the strange one .
Why , because I have feelings ?
' Cause I feel ?
There 's someone at the door .
( knocking )
I won 't answer that .
Whoever it is , they can come back at the end of the hour .
That 's for me .
Sorry , I have to interrupt .
We need your help , Dan .
I know . Uh ...
gotta go ,
( train horn blaring )
( suspenseful orchestral music )
( gasping , whimpering )
( sobbing )
( crying )
( screaming )
( helicopter whirring )
Mr. Fitch will be with you all in just a moment .
Well ,
I guess we all must be here for the same reason ,
whatever that is .
I 'm Dan Smithson .
And I don 't know why I 'm here either .
But , um , they said they needed me
and that it was very important , so I came .
What do you do , Dan ?
I ... -
am an empath ..
Sometimes they show me awful things
that people have done .
And then I try to tell them why they did it .
What qualifies you for that ?
I feel things deeply , that 's all .
What am I feeling right now ?
You wanna believe that nothing affects you , that ...
( chuckling ) you 're not afraid of anything .
But you 're curious ,
just like the rest of us .
( clears throat ) Stephen Arden ,
Harvard Anthropology Department .
Expert at cross-cultural behavior .
Laura Baker , hi .
Molecular biologist , hi .
And who are you and what do you do ?
Preston Lennox .
And if I 'm here ,
I think the shit has definitely hit the fan .
What exactly is your area of specialty , Mr. Lennox ?
Let 's just say I 'm a freelance solution
to some of our government 's problems .
( chuckling )
And what exactly might they be ?
The kind that people don 't usually like to talk about .
You hunt people , don 't you ?
I guess so .
( knocking )
You in here , honey , it 's a little late for T.V. - -
You in here , honey ?
( distant thunder roaring )
( screaming )
( train horn blaring )
( suspenseful orchestral music )
Good evening .
I 'm Xavier Fitch .
I 'm in charge of this operation .
Would you sit a little closer , please ?
In November of 1974 ,
a small group from SETI , S-E-T-I ,
Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence ,
used the radio dishes at Arecibo
to send out a message to whoever might be listening .
They sent about a quarter of a kilobyte ,
including structure of human DNA ,
map of our solar system ,
population of the Earth , you know , helpful facts like that .
In January of 1993 ,
Arecibo received a message back
from an extraterrestrial unknown source .
That 's great .
Intelligent life beyond this planet ?
FITCH : Yes .
There were two distinct communications .
The first message turned out to be
a superior catalyst from methane .
We now have the potential to produce
an infinite amount of energy from this clean-burning fuel .
This convinced us that we were dealing
with a friendly intelligence .
The second message turned out to be a new sequence of DNA
with a rather friendly instructions
on how to combine it with ours .
Here 's some technical data on the whole operation .
You can get feedback on it from Dr. Baker here .
Basically , the new combined DNA sequence
was injected into 100 human ova .
We got seven to divide .
Four petered out .
Two were stored in liquid nitrogen .
And we allowed one to grow .
That 's its code name there , Sil .
That 's after two hours .
One day .
Two days .
My God !
Its growth is amazing .
FITCH : It 's a week .
- It 's a girl . - Yes , I ...
We decided to make it female
so that it would be more docile and controllable .
PRESS : More docile and controllable , huh ?
Well , I guess you guys don 't get out much .
That 's her one month after she was born .
So you kept her caged in there ?
We decided it would be safer to keep her in isolation .
She didn 't like being locked up like that .
She didn 't like being alone like that .
Didn 't she ?
She 's hiding something , something inside .
You 're right , Dan .
This is three months after she was born
and you watch carefully .
( sonic twittering )
What the hell was that ?
Back the tape up .
Watch her eyes .
Rapid eye movement , she 's dreaming .
( sonic twittering )
She 's having horrible nightmares .
It 's some kind of anxiety reaction .
Got me a little anxious .
Well , it made the research team a little anxious , too ,
so , the decision was made to terminate the experiment
to run more research so that we could determine
what we were dealing with .
You were going to gas her ?
That was the decision .
DAN : It makes you feel mad .
It makes you feel mad you had to kill her , doesn 't it ?
I don 't know .
Wow .
Yes .
Yesterday morning , the body of a transient
was found in a boxcar in a sighting near Salt Lake City .
Preliminary DNA tests conclude
he was killed by our creation , by our Sil .
Have you found any other bodies ?
- No , we haven 't , not yet . - DAN : You will .
She 's a predator .
Her eyes are in front .
Her eyes are in front so she can judge
the distance to her prey .
That 's right .
Where 'd you learn that fact , Dan ?
I saw it on a documentary on the Discovery Channel .
I caught that show myself .
- FITCH : Mr. Lennox . - Yeah .
As the , um , well , the non-scientist amongst us ,
are you at all clear about what 's going on here ?
Oh , I think so .
You created a monster
from some kind of formula you got from outer space .
The damn thing got away ,
and now you want us to hunt it down and kill it .
Now , is that pretty close ?
I guess .
LAURA : Wait a minute , you don 't want us
to capture her alive so that we can study her ?
Laura , I think this is strictly a
search-and-destroy operation .
Nobody ever asked me to find anything they didn 't want dead .
I 'm sorry for you .
Yeah , well , thank you , Dan .
I 'm sorry for her .
MAN ON P.A. : Ladies and gentlemen ,
may I have your attention , please ?
Welcome to Los Angeles , California .
This is the terminal stop for the Desert Star .
All passengers , please disembark .
( fast beat thumping music )
( chattering , crying )
( helicopter whirring )
Something bad happened here .
Oh , shit , crushed her larynx .
She was afraid .
She 's scared , she 's frightened .
ARDEN : Hungry , too , by the looks of it ,
she 's been eating like a horse .
Well , our girl is definitely not on a diet .
She must be storing up calories for something .
Any ideas ?
Oh , my . '
Well , that 's a ...
That looks like some sort of ( clears throat )
chrysalis , some kind of cocoon .
What are we looking for , a giant moth ?
If that is a cocoon , she 'll be fully grown now .
Fully grown .
Well , maybe that 's how she got by our people .
They were looking for a child .
She is a child .
It stinks in here .
I 'm going outside .
Get the conductor 's ID and credit card numbers
on your computer .
There 's no sign of them on the train .
Let 's assume she took them with her .
I 'll see to that .
She kills if she feels threatened .
And she has no remorse about it .
None .
Of course , Los Angeles is perfect for her .
It 's a city of the future .
Anything goes .
Totally mobile population . Everyone 's a stranger .
Very little in this town is taboo or unacceptable .
Whatever she does , no one 's going to notice .
Yeah , well , whatever , so ...
Los Angeles is where the battle is gonna be fought ,
and won .
( music playing )
SALESWOMAN : You look very pretty .
Do you have a hundred ?
Here we are .
You ought to be more careful with your money .
Not everybody 's as honest as me .
Are you foreign ?
Do you speak English ?
Yes .
Here , you keep this .
Here , let me take this .
Be careful here .
Yes .
( tires screeching )
Watch your step .
Our laboratory , Visitor Base One is being moved
two blocks from here to some empty virus research labs
at the university .
They 're moving our equipment as we speak .
It 'll be operational by eight o 'clock .
Check into your rooms .
Everyone out front in 15 minutes .
We 'll go on over .
What exactly are we gonna do when we go on over ?
Process the evidence we collected on the train .
Couldn 't we try growing this creature
with just its own DNA ?
We make up a version without including ours this time
so we can investigate its vulnerabilities ?
That 'd be good .
Then I could know how it feels .
ARDEN : It makes sense .
This human life form could be a mask .
If we could see it without the camouflage - -
You 're right , you 're right , you 're right .
Then at least we 'd know what we were dealing with .
( suspenseful music )
( screeching , honking )
A couple of bozos just ran out .
I got a customer , call you back .
Yes , young lady , can I help you ?
I want a room .
$ 62 , including tax .
That should just about cover the honeymoon suite .
( crashing )
Hi , come here often ?
What 's your sign ?
Tired of brunette ?
Change .
Change the color of your hair .
Color-Tress .
Okay , I 've just increased the magnification .
When I pierce the cell , the foreign DNA will be introduced .
( popping ) Shit !
The camera 's just gone down . Um ...
EXCUSE me .
Do you have a replacement camera ?
We have a standby camera
but it will take some time for the technician
to come by and replace it .
Oh , no , this happens in my lab all the time .
It 's a simple operation to replace it .
Are you saying you can do it ?
Well , yeah , sure I can .
I just need somebody to give me a hand .
Well , I don 't want technicians in there .
This is classified .
I 'll do it .
- Man of action , I like that . - That 's me .
Can you get that one for me ?
Give me the camera .
( low suspenseful music )
Something 's , something 's wrong .
Christ , it 's started already .
It 's started already , get the top back on .
What ?
Laura , Press , get the top back on .
Here you go .
She must have penetrated the cell
when the camera went down .
( clattering )
- PRESS : Shit . - LAURA : What was that ?
He dropped the bolt .
Find the bolt . Get the top back on .
I 'm looking , Fitch .
Can they hear me in there ?
Laura , Press , get the top back on ,
then I 'm gonna let you out of the room .
LAURA : Where 'd it go ?
PRESS : I think it fell through the grate .
FITCH : Can you lift up the grate ?
PRESS : It 's not gonna move .
LAURA : This isn 't going anywhere .
PRESS : No , I can 't get it .
Press , you gotta get the bolt out from under the grate !
PRESS : I can 't get to it .
The floor 's welded down .
LAURA : Oh , my God .
Press , oh , my God , I 've never seen anything like this .
PRESS : Holy shit .
I can 't let them out of the room .
LAURA : Press , look .
PRESS : Come on .
Fitch , let us out of here !
Open the goddamn door !
Can 't let you out
- until I know what 's in there . - LAURA : Open the door now !
- You gotta let them out . - I can 't do that .
- PRESS : Open up the fucking door ! - LAURA : Let us out !
Tell me it 's gonna stop growing , Dan . Tell me it 's gonna stop growing .
It 's not , let them out !
( banging )
PRESS : Open up the door !
- Press , Press . - ( hissing )
PRESS : What the fuck is that ?
Laura , get to the other door !
Let her out , Fitch !
- I can 't let her out , Press . - PRESS : Let her out !
- I can 't do that . - PRESS : You motherfucker !
You fool , would you let her out !
ARDEN : You 've gotta let them out , Fitch !
- PRESS : I can 't hold it in ! - Get out of the way !
I 'm gonna burn it ! Get out of the way !
( blasting ) ( screaming )
PRESS : What is this thing ?
Guys , it 's grown in two minutes .
I 'll have to burn the whole room .
I have to , I have to burn the whole room .
You got less than two minutes to kill the thing .
Disconnect the gas line in the isolation box .
Use it as a flamethrower .
( bursting )
( clamoring )
PRESS : Laura , watch out !
Where did it go ?
LAURA : It 's in the pipe .
- Open the door ! - Shut up , Dan !
( electricity crackling )
VOICE : One minute remaining .
PRESS : Laura , it stopped moving .
I think I killed it .
It 's dead , open the door .
It 's dead , Fitch , let them out .
Oh , God , it 's not dead .
LAURA : What are we gonna do ?
VOICE : 30 seconds remaining .
PRESS : There 's not much time .
- We gotta get out of here . - Open the door !
You gotta let them out .
I can 't do that , it might escape .
- I have to follow protocol . - What protocol ?
The protocols by which we 're running these experiments .
You didn 't tell them that before they went in there .
- Fitch , let them out . - VOICE : 12 , 11 , 10 .
- Fitch , let them out ! - I have to follow protocol .
Let them out , Fitch !
Go , get out of there !
VOICE : Three , two , one .
I hope you realize that I had no choice .
Yeah , sure .
The protocol is to burn the room in two minutes
if anything went wrong .
( T.V. playing in background )
Where 's a good place to find a man ?
Well , there 's plenty of guys at the Id around the corner .
It 's a club .
You won 't have any trouble meeting somebody there .
Thank you .
You can 't miss it , just look for the long line .
Oh , hey , I need your credit card
for room incidentals , long distance calls ,
damage to the room and so forth .
Credit card ?
Zip zap ?
Plastic , American Express , Visa , MasterCard ?
There you go .
Thanks , all right .
Angel .
Oh , hey , wait a minute , hey , hey .
You don 't want this falling into the wrong hands .
No .
ANNOUNCER : Here 's Justin Crawl ,
holes it in , hit shot comes through
- and it 's covered by the - - - ( phone rings )
Yeah ?
The conductor 's stolen credit card
has turned up at a motel in Hollywood .
The Van 's out front , let 's go .
( tires screeching )
You two .
Enjoy yourselves .
You , legs , you 're in , go on .
( upbeat party music )
Hey , hey , where are you from ?
- I 'm foreign . - You 're what ?
- I 'm foreign . - Foreign , really ?
Oh , ho , easy , easy .
I 've got a party to go to and no one to take me .
I 'll take you .
- WOMAN : You will ? - MAN : Yeah .
Okay , I 'm going to go to the little girls ' room .
You wait right here .
I 'll be right back .
MAN : I 'll be right here .
Whatever it takes , right ?
Hey , all 's fair in love and war .
( chuckling )
( crashing ) ( yelping )
( screaming ) ( upbeat party music )
PRESS : Can 't see much on that .
Get this tape back to the lab , enhance it .
Let 's see if we can get a better look at her .
She looks nice .
Do you have any idea where she went ?
I 'll find her .
CLERK : She wanted to know where she could meet a man .
I sort of mentioned , suggested a club called the Id
around the corner .
Get the tape .
( upbeat party music )
I 've got a party to go to and no one to take me .
Where is this party ?
I don 't know .
( screaming )
( helicopter whirring ) ( tires screeching )
Whoa , whoa , whoa , you can 't park there .
Back that out .
No , you can 't go in there .
Hey , hey , hey , what 's going on here ?
( door banging open )
( car engine starting )
WOMAN : There 's a murderer in the club !
Nobody leaves the club , and I mean , nobody !
( helicopter whirring )
There 's always some action in this part of town .
( music playing in car )
PRESS : Blue-eyed blonde .
Black leggings , pink sweater , five-foot , 10 inches tall .
Who 'd she leave with ?
Blue eyed blonde leaves with a guy , it 's hardly news around here .
Just name the top attractions , the regulars , no losers .
You should assume he 's socially adept .
He 'll be helping her out - -
We 're looking for a friendly guy , not a total asshole .
BOUNCER : I 'm thinking , I 'm thinking .
Robbie left with a blonde .
DAN : That 's him .
That 's him .
Come on , let me show you the rest of the house .
Oh , I 'm still sweaty from that place .
It 's so crowded .
Like it ?
Yes .
I feel like a shower .
You want one ?
Tell you what .
I 'm gonna take one .
You wanna get in and take one later ?
No problem .
Take off your clothes .
I want to see you .
Very nice .
Can you drive me back ?
What are you talking about ?
You knew what we came here for .
I 've changed my mind .
All right , you said no .
It 's duly noted .
- Come here . - I said I wanna go .
Too late , babe . You 're not leaving .
I said you 're not leaving .
- All right . - That 's better .
( mellow suspenseful music )
( muffled grunting )
( bursting )
( showering )
( soft suspenseful music )
( suspenseful music )
What 's happening ?
Kills a girl at the club , comes home with this guy
and kills him .
Well , I 'd say she fits the classic definition
of a psychopath .
She 's got nothing to inhibit her .
No moral sense , no social structure .
She wasn 't exactly smothered with a mother 's love
or taught good manners , you know what I mean ?
FITCH : I asked what was happening .
He did something to her , she was angry .
She 'll kill if she feels threatened .
She 'll kill anyone that gets in her way .
Gets in her way of what ?
LAURA : Her life cycle .
I think she 's trying to mate .
Reproduce .
Okay -
So why did she kill the girl at the club ?
Sexual competition .
She 's pretty hard on the competition .
And now she 's managed to mate .
It doesn 't look like a successful mating to me .
He 's still got his pants on .
She 's frustrated .
Who isn 't ?
What is her problem ? He was here , she was here .
LAURA : All right , maybe she rejected him .
She probably has some special kind of senses .
Rats can sense diseased or genetic damage
in their potential mates ,
so we can test his body for any hereditary diseases ,
any defects that would have made him a loser , essentially .
Needles .
Maybe he was some kind of a doper , or diabetic .
Yeah , well , either way would make him unacceptable .
Excuse me .
All right .
Insulin , diabetic , there you have it .
She could have just walked out . Why did she have to kill him ?
Well , I guess he pissed her off .
Some men don 't like to be rejected .
They get insistent .
Put an APB out on this guy 's car .
PRESS : It 's already happened .
We 'll go back to the motel .
I wanna check it out thoroughly .
More docile and controllable , huh , Fitch ?
What do you think , Dan ?
What do I think ?
I think she 'd wanna be alone right now .
I don 't think she 's gonna wanna come here
with all these cars lined up out front .
Well , you are assuming
that she could find her way back here .
- DAN : She could . - What is it ?
Maybe menstrual blood .
If she 's menstruating , she 's definitely
capable of reproduction .
Yes , I know .
( loud ominous music )
( panting )
( car engine starting )
( music playing on radio )
( car sputtering , dies )
( boy whistling )
( tires screeching )
( crashing ) ( glass shattering )
Oh , Jesus . Excuse me .
MAN : Call a paramedic . Anybody got a phone ?
MAN ON RADIO : If your homeward commute takes you
westbound on the Santa Monica 10 freeway ,
expect delays of up to one hour .
The homeward drive is going to be slow
for people who are heading to Malibu , PCH is - -
( beeping )
FITCH : The video enhancement is not all that great .
ARDEN : How old do you think she is ?
20 , 23 ?
Her reproductive system should be fully developed .
Her biological clock must be in hyperdrive .
She wants to have a baby .
ARDEN : Well , if she manages to have a child ,
our problems have just started .
If her offspring 's male
and it develops at the same accelerated rate as Sil ,
it could be capable of reproduction
in less than six months .
God knows how many females it could impregnate .
Fitch .
You see , when a predatory species is introduced
into a closed ecological system ,
the extinction of the weaker species is inevitable .
They found the murdered guy 's BMW .
It ran out of gas in Santa Monica .
And what is her name ?
I don 't know her name .
So who are you ?
You know , she didn 't have any ID on her
so I just thought I 'd come by to make sure she was okay .
NURSE : Do you think she 's got insurance ?
I don 't know .
Here , just put it on my credit card for the time being .
And you don 't know her name .
Guys like you are hard to find .
Get a lab workup on that , stat .
Arrange to get her up to X-ray . I want an X-ray on this .
It looks like a scapula fracture .
DOCTOR : Your shoulder ...
What 's going on here ?
Doctor , we need you immediately .
A child burn victim just came in .
What is going on here ?
- Doctor , please . - Jesus Christ !
Did you see her shoulder ?
Doctor , please , we need you immediately .
( suspenseful music )
You 're okay .
I 'm okay .
Well , I was sure you were seriously injured .
You are , it 's a miracle .
Can we go ?
Did the doctor say you could go ?
Yes .
Yeah , we 'll look at it , we 'll send somebody over there .
Thanks a lot .
A report 's come in .
Doctor over at Parkbay Hospital called in with some weird story .
We should check it out . It 's only a couple of miles from here .
Laura , Press , take a car , check it out .
- Parkbay Hospital ? - Yeah , Parkbay .
She walked .
She walked that way , not too long ago .
Got some fruit and cheese here .
What is that ?
What , do you mean the hot tub ?
A hot tub .
I love this place .
It 's away from the traffic and the business
and all the people .
Sometimes it feels like you 're not in L.A. anymore .
Here .
We 'll immortalize the moment .
( beeping )
Look at the camera .
( camera clicks )
( gasping )
DOCTOR : This girl literally reformed her bone structure .
It 's her .
Who checked her in ?
I don 't know , let 's find out .
She had no insurance , so this guy
put it on his own credit card .
Here 's the file .
John F. Carey .
You haven 't got a driver 's license , home address ,
Social Security number , anything like that ?
NURSE : No , sir .
I only got an imprint of his credit card .
That 's the only information I have .
Can you give us a printout of whatever you 've got ?
No problem .
Some candy ?
( keyboard keys clicking )
All right , it 's an address in the Palisades
and he 's got a phone number .
Tell Fitch where we 're headed ,
and try to get John Carey on the line .
( tires screeching )
- ( opera music ) - ( hot tub water gurgling )
( phone ringing )
I better get the phone .
I 've got his machine . Should I leave a message ?
Yeah .
Tell him he 's about to copulate with a creature from outer space .
( laughing )
- Copulate , huh ? - Yeah .
- I like you . - I know .
It 's not too soon for us to be together .
No , it 's not too soon .
You don 't need these .
Hey , hey , that 's a little fast .
Whoa , whoa , whoa , whoa .
( laughing )
What 's the matter ?
Take it easy .
Just relax .
There 's plenty of time .
( door knob clicking )
What is it ?
Oh , no , I think someone 's at the door .
Don 't go .
Please , I want a baby .
What ? Excuse me ?
( gulping ) ( Splashing )
Let 's go around the side .
( hissing )
- ( gasping ) - ( growling )
( grunting )
( mouthing ) Outside .
( gasps )
( suspenseful orchestral music )
( muted growling )
_ ( squeaking ) - ( screaming )
What happened ?
A squirrel , it was a fucking squirrel .
She was here .
Yeah , she was .
I wanna make sure she 's not still here .
( helicopter whirring )
( low growling )
ARDEN : Perhaps we should check the body
for any evidence that they 've had sex .
DAN : I used to be scared at the sight of blood .
Now I guess I 'm getting used to it .
Oh , yes .
( car alarm chirps )
( car door shuts )
- Hey ! - You gotta help me , please .
Oh , my God , what 's the matter ?
We found this in the living room .
She liked him .
Well , not enough .
Can 't see any more on that than we did on the video monitor .
FITCH : He didn 't get a very good picture of her , did he ?
Criminologist says there 's no evidence
of semen in the hot tub water .
Oh , maybe she took it with .
So she probably hasn 't managed to mate .
We - - we interrupted her .
Yes , I think we did .
Give me something I can use .
What have you come up with lately , Fitch ?
She 's not scared of us .
That 's for sure .
We 're all beat .
We 'll go back to the hotel , get some rest .
Tomorrow night , we 'll go back to the club .
- Stake it out . - SIL : Stake it out .
Ah , she 's not stupid .
She 's not gonna repeat herself .
There 's no point in going back there .
It provided such a poor specimen .
I 'm not so sure .
Look , she 's been in the city two days .
It 's what she knows .
And I 'd rather try the club than sit around
the command center reminiscing about how close we got .
She would make one excellent biological weapon .
If someone out there thought
we were some kind of galactic weed
that was going to spread through the universe .
So what you 're saying is that
she 's the cure and we 're the disease .
That 's well said . ( chuckling )
Baker , Laura .
1735 Meander Drive , Simi Valley , California .
That 's you , right ?
Last time I checked .
What do you do for kicks out there in Simi Valley ?
Oh , pine for guys like you .
That 's what I thought . ( laughing )
So , anyone hungry ?
No , thanks , I 'm beat .
I 'm just gonna try to get some sleep .
Good night .
Yeah , night .
I 'll have something to eat with you .
Thanks , Dan .
( ominous music )
( electricity crackling )
( gasping )
( whimpering )
Do you ever have nightmares ?
Yes .
Please untie my hands .
I wouldn 't hurt you , please .
I have them .
I think they tell me who I am .
Why are you doing this to me ?
I don 't know why I 'm here .
I don 't know who I am , who sent me .
- Do you ? - No .
- Why do you think you 're here ? - I don 't know .
Please let me go , please , please let me go .
I wouldn 't hurt you .
I promise .
- I wouldn 't hurt you . - Yes , you would .
You just don 't know it yet .
No , I wouldn 't .
Please . ( sobbing )
My hands are hurting me .
Thank you . Thank you .
( whimpering )
Oh. my God !
" ( Sobbing ) ' ( clinks )
No , stop . ( sobbing )
Oh , my God .
No !
No ! ( screams )
( pensive orchestral music )
( birds chirping )
( tires screeching )
( splashing )
( upbeat party music )
DAN : Laura and Press , they like each other .
They just don 't like to show how they feel , you know ?
What ?
Laura and Press , they like each other .
ARDEN : Yeah , whatever you say , Dan .
Look , it 's really smoky in here .
I 'm gonna go outside , get a bit of air .
Think I 'll lie down in the back of the van , have a rest .
This is a complete waste of time .
You get a feeling you 're on a wild goose chase .
Yeah .
Excuse me .
( suspenseful music )
" ( yells )
BUM : Get out of here . This is our trashcan .
It 's you .
Hey !
She 's here !
( car engine starting )
- Dan , is that her ? - Yeah , here .
( crashing )
FITCH : Get in the van !
FITCH : Everybody get in the van !
( tires screeching )
( crashing )
They 're heading into the hills .
We 'll need the helicopters .
( helicopters whirring )
( tires screeching )
Yeah , we 're going up , uh , Nichols Canyon .
One of you try to block her at Mulholland .
( helicopters whirring )
( tires screeching )
- ( splashing ) - ( whimpering )
LAURA : Watch it !
( woman whimpering )
( screaming )
( explosion )
Oh , my God !
( helicopters whirring )
( missiles firing )
( explosions )
- ( horns honking ) - ( sirens blaring )
We blocked the road in both directions .
The press is going apeshit . We gotta tell them something .
Well , you tell them what you want ,
you just don 't tell them the truth .
I don 't buy her showing up at the club like that .
It 's too damn convenient .
Well , seeing is believing , or don 't you trust your own eyes ?
Get back .
Get all these people back .
Fitch , Fitch , it doesn 't feel right .
Sir !
We found what looks like a severed thumb
in the pocket of one of the doors that got ripped off .
Let me see that .
She may have caught it in the door trying to get out .
We 'll get it over to the lab .
If it 's hers , it 'll check out .
It 'll be genetically identifiable .
It 's all over , everyone .
Tomorrow , you can go back to your lives .
Congratulations on a job well done .
Just like that , huh , Fitch ?
I don 't think so .
( phone ringing )
[ Woman 's voice recording ] Hi , Sharp boys .
Leave me a message , okay ?
And Frank , I 'm going to dinner .
Where are we meeting ?
Bye , sweetie .
Waiter .
Well , I guess we won .
We won , science lost .
I didn 't think we 'd get her this way .
Not that easy .
You sound like you 're going to miss her .
PRESS : Yeah , well , I guess I will .
I think I respected her .
Look , I know this has been a hellish job , you know ,
but I 've - - I 've really enjoyed working with you three .
And seeing as Uncle Sam is buying the drinks ,
why don 't we have another round ? Hmm ?
Waiter !
I don 't , I don 't drink , Arden .
Don 't worry , Dan , tonight you will .
You wanna dance ?
Who , me ?
Yeah , you .
- All right . - ( laughs ) Okay .
♫ If you don 't know me by now
♫ You will never never never know me
♫ You 'll never know
I know you don 't have a family .
So do you have a girlfriend in New York ?
I guess I 've had a few ,
but they don 't hang around very long .
I guess I keep too many secrets .
You wanna share one with me ?
- Right now ? - Mm-hmm .
Well , I know what you do , and it doesn 't scare me .
- Really ? - No .
Well , it does most people .
I wouldn 't wanna never see you again .
- Hey ! - ( glasses clattering )
I 'm sorry , I 'm sorry .
I thought you were somebody else .
I 'm sorry .
You Okay ?
I thought it was her , I thought it was Sil .
I saw the blonde hair .
LAURA : She 's dead , Press .
The tests on the thumb proved it was her .
Yeah , well , you got your test and I got my gut .
And I just don 't buy it .
Well , you wanna know what I think ?
I think as long as you feel that she 's out there ,
you got a mission .
And maybe you don 't want this job to be over .
Uh-huh . Well , maybe not .
So what ?
Thanks for the dance .
Good night .
What do you call this ?
It 's called a Long Island Iced Tea .
It 's got tea in it ?
Nope .
( laughing )
Smells nice , can I try some ?
Help yourself .
Does it work on your boyfriend ?
Yeah , as a repellent .
I don 't know .
I think he 's in remarkably good shape for a man his age .
One Long Island Iced Tea .
I like these cup - - these cups of tea .
( chuckling )
What ?
That 's great .
What ? What ?
( chuckling )
I like these cups of tea , man .
You guys , I 'm tired .
I 'm gonna go to bed .
So ?
She 's going to bed .
I guess .
She still
wants to see you , though .
Maybe I 'll go find out if you 're right about that .
( suspenseful music )
I 'd hate to be in one of these things during an earthquake .
Yeah .
What floor do you want ?
10 , please .
I like your perfume .
You do ?
Thank you .
Excuse me , I get out here .
Good night .
( knocking )
Yes !
- Hi . - Hi .
( suspenseful orchestral music )
Did you want something ?
Maybe .
Maybe ?
( thuds )
( laughing )
( thud ) ( laughing )
( keys clinking )
( knocking ) Housekeeping .
Dan .
Those two over there .
Bet they like unusual men like us .
DAN : Women think I 'm strange .
I don 't feel well .
Don 't be silly .
Just go over there and talk to ' em .
I have to go .
And I think you should leave with me , okay ?
I 'm gonna stay for a while , actually .
Okay -
I 'll see you tomorrow .
( knocking ) Housekeeping .
( suspenseful music )
( muffled laughing )
Hi .
- Hi . - Hi .
I couldn 't help noticing sitting over there ,
you know , I was wondering what two very intelligent ,
glamorous-looking women were doing without dates .
My name 's Stephen Arden , by the way .
I teach Comparative Anthropology at Harvard .
- I lived in Boston once . - Yeah ?
For a year .
Froze my butt off .
I like it cold in Boston .
This is Bill and Tony .
I forget your name .
Nice socks .
( laughing )
Stand up .
Whoo !
( electricity crackling )
( pensive orchestral music )
How 'd you get in here ?
- I stole the key . - What ?
I saw you downstairs , but you were with all those people .
So I thought I 'd come up and wait .
Well ...
This kind of thing doesn 't usually happen to me .
- I just want to be with you . - Huh ?
Oh , yes .
( chuckling )
( thud )
What about protection ?
( electricity crackling )
( moaning , panting )
( suspenseful orchestral music )
( electricity crackling )
She 's here , she 's here .
( knocking )
- Press ? - Hmm ?
Someone 's at the door .
( knocking )
Who 's there ?
Press , Laura .
It 's Dan , I gotta talk to you .
Oh Christ , what does he want ?
What 's the problem , Dan ?
I just got this terrible feeling .
I just get this strange thought ,
you know , this image of Sil with Arden .
Sil 's next door to Arden , Press .
No , no , no , no . She 's dead , Dan .
You don 't understand . I got a little upset ,
so I went to his room and there 's somebody
in his room with him .
Did you knock on the door ?
I knocked on the door , but I don 't know what she 'll do to him , you know .
All I know is they 're making a lot of noise .
They 're having sex .
And I know it 's Sil , Press .
I know it 's Sil , I know it !
Okay , I believe you .
I 'm gonna get dressed .
( electricity crackling )
( moaning )
Oh , my God .
Well , I enjoyed that immensely .
I felt it .
What ?
It 's started .
What 's started ?
Life .
( chuckling ) Oh , my darling girl .
I know in some cultures , women believe
they know the exact moment of conception .
- But really ( chuckles ) . - Don 't you believe me ?
Feel .
Holy shit .
- ( screaming ) - ( growling )
I hope you 're right about this , Dan .
( banging ) ( shattering )
( gunfire )
She 's headed for the basement .
Take the stairs .
Laura , come with me .
Come on !
If she 's pregnant , we gotta get to her
before she gives birth .
God , we don 't know what we 're dealing with here .
She could have a dozen babies .
She could lay 1,000 eggs .
Oh , God .
Did you see Arden ?
Yeah , I did , that poor bastard .
They can make it , we have a trap .
The fire doors can only be opened from the inside
of the bottom exit .
Then what ?
- Holy shit . - Oh , my God .
The bitch went right through a steel door .
Fitch , Dan , we 're in the garage !
She got past us !
( gunfire ) ( glass shattering )
You saw her ?
She was gone before we got here .
Here .
You saw her ?
Look at the door .
- Which way did she go ? - I don 't know .
Where 's Press ?
He took off down that tunnel .
( screaming in distance )
She kills if she feels threatened .
( loud clatter )
She must have come through here .
( ominous music )
PRESS : She went down here , there 's no other way .
Yeah , she 's down there .
Let 's go .
Stand back , I 'll clear it out .
( flames roaring )
Which way do you think she went , Dan ?
- I don 't know . - What ?
I 'm not sure . She 's here .
Think about it , for Christ 's sake .
You 're supposed to have some extrasensory powers
that can tell us all which way did she go .
Which way did she go , Dan ?
Which way did she go ?
- I don 't know , I don 't know . - Where did she go ?
She went that way .
- You think ? - That 's good enough for me .
You think she went that way ?
You don 't fucking know , do you ? You don 't fucking know .
I 'm going this way . You come with me .
Come with me , Dan !
Fitch .
I think she went this way .
( water gurgling )
Dan ?
- ( bursting ) - ( yelping )
Fitch , Fitch !
Dan ?
What happened ?
( gasping )
I can feel her .
She 's that way .
I never thought I 'd want to kill something .
Never thought I 'd want to kill something .
( low growling )
( suspenseful music )
Hey .
It 's this way .
It 's back here .
- ( screaming ) - ( splashing )
Hey , she went in here .
This must have opened up during the earthquake .
Okay , stand back .
( fire roaring )
( growling )
( shrill crying )
( fire roaring )
PRESS : Wow !
LAURA : Is that oil ?
PRESS : Looks like it .
I 'm gonna go on back through there
and see if I can flush her out .
If she comes back through here , let her have it .
LAURA : Dan , Dan !
LAURA : ( whispering ) Dan , what is it ?
( whispering ) I don 't know . I don 't know .
( baby cooing )
( rat squeaking )
Dan .
( grunting )
Okay -
It 's okay .
Nobody 's gonna hurt you .
You come here .
What ? Come on , I got you .
( yelping ) ( thud )
Press , something 's happened to Dan !
You Okay ?
( splashing )
Shit !
Dan ?
I 'm stuck !
Press !
I need your help , I 'm stuck !
( growling )
( flames roaring )
( yelping )
( growling )
Press !
Dan , you 've got to hang on .
Dan , hang on .
- ( growling ) - ( grunting )
( coughing )
Press !
( grunting )
( grunting ) ( knife clanking )
- Shit ! - ( hissing )
LAURA : Dan , hang on !
( growling ) ( firing )
( screaming )
Hang on , Dan .
Hang on .
Laura , you okay ?
I got you .
I got you , Dan , hang on .
Oh , shit .
( roaring )
( screaming )
PRESS : Hang on !
Hang on , Dan !
LAURA : Get rid of her , Press !
Duck your head !
Let go , you motherfucker .
( grenade firing )
I got you , hold on , I got you .
Oh , shit .
( splashing )
I thought I was dead .
I thought you 'd drank your last
Long Island Iced Tea there , Dan .
LAURA : Yeah , I thought we all had .
Hey , you okay ?
Yeah , I 'm okay .
My pants are a little messed up .
But I 'm okay .
LAURA : She was half us , half something else .
I wonder which was the predatory half .
The dead half .
Let 's get the hell out of here .
( somber orchestral music )
( sighing )
I never thought I 'd be so happy to be back in a sewer .
( squeaking )
( suspenseful music )
( somber orchestral music )